Guide to the Ruth Fulton Benedict Papers, 1857-1958
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- SERIES XI. NATIVE AMERICAN SUBJECT FILES, Some of this material is available online at Alexander Street Press's Anthropology Commons.
  - GENERAL
    - Pima Mythology - Twin Sons of Rain, (fragment) (Folder 81.15)
    - Pima Mythology - The Two Brothers/Coyote Eats His Own Bowels, undated (Folder 81.16)
    - Pima Mythology - War of the Coyotes Against the Sun/Coyote and Buzzard, undated (Folder 81.17)
    - Pima Mythology - War Ritual, undated (Folder 81.18)
    - Acoma Drawings, undated (Folders 82.1-82.36)
    - The Boy Who Broke His Vows, (TS) (Folder 83.1)
    - The Cumaakoli Mask, (TS) (Folder 83.2)
    - The Curing Contest of Cumaakol and Kokotana, (TS) (Folder 83.3)
    - They Dance for Rain in Zuñi, (TS) (Folder 83.4)
    - The Drought, (TS) (Folder 83.5)
    - Emergence Myths, (TS) (Folder 83.6)
    - Fire Dance, (TS) (Folder 83.7)
    - How They Brought the Curing Societies from Cipapolima, (TS) (Folders 83.8-83.11)
    - The Kianakwe Dance, (TS) (Folder 84.1)
    - The Lahewe Dance, (TS) (Folder 84.2)
    - The Santu, (TS) (folder 84.3)
    - The Solo Dancers of Wotemta, (TS) (Folder 84.4)
    - The Tcakwena Dance, (TS) (Folder 84.5)
    - Sun Priest, (TS) (Folder 84.6-84.8)
    - Miscellaneous Zuñi Pictures, undated (Folder 84.9)
    - Zuñi Costume drawings, undated (Folder 84.10)
    - Zuñi Notes, undated (Folder 85.1)
    - Totem Dakotas, (TS) (Folder 86.1)
    - Dakota Sioux - Social Organization -- The Kinship System, (TS) (Folder 86.2)
    - Dakota Sioux - Social Organization -- Kinship Categories, (TS) (Folder 86.3)
    - Dakota Sioux - Social Organization -- More Characteristic Behavior, (TS) (Folder 86.4)
    - Dakota Sioux - Kinship Notes, undated (Folder 86.5)
    - The Indians of North and South Dakota (Brownlee and Johnson), undated (Folder 86.6)
    - Seminar on Indian Work, 1941 (Folder 86.7)
    - Assiniboine Report (Ella Deloria), (TS) (Folder 86.8-86.12)
    - Blackfoot Field Trip, 1939 (Folder 86.13)
    - Blackfoot Field Trip, 1939 (Folder 86.14)
    - Religion of the North American Indians, Notes, undated (Folder 87.1)
    - Religion of the North American Indians, Notes, undated (Folder 87.2)
    - Religion of the North American Indians, Outline and Synopsis, (TS) (Folder 87.3)
    - Religion of the North American Indians. Chapter 1, (TS) (Folder 87.4)
    - Religion of the North American Indians. Chapter 2, (TS) (Folder 87.5)
    - Religion of the North American Indians. Chapter 3, (TS) (Folder 87.6)
    - Religion of the North American Indians. Chapter 5, (TS) (Folder 87.7)
  - NORTH AMERICAN INDIAN FOLKLORE
    - The Bears Killed for Their Father, (TS) (Folder 88.1)
    - The Dancers Bring Out a Dead Hand, (TS) (Folder 88.2)
    - How a Man Obtains His Mask, (TS) (Folder 88.3)
    - The Lame and the Blind, (TS) (Folder 88.4)
    - The Man Who Refused Power from Yosin, (TS) (Folder 88.5)
    - Medicine Talk of the Stick Swallowing Order of the Big Fire Society, (TS) (Folder 88.6)
    - The Ojibwa Brother-Gods, (TS) (Folder 88.7)
    - The Orphan Children, (TS) (Folder 88.8)
    - The Rabbit Hunt, (TS) (Folder 88.9)
    - Scalp Dance, (TS, fragment) (Folder 88.10)
    - The Visit of Kialko, (TS) (Folder 88.11)
    - Notes, undated (Folder 88.12)
    - Drawings, undated (Folder 88.13)
    - Drawings, undated (Folder 88.14)
    - Photographs and clippings of illustrations of Native American [see also folder 123.17], undated (Folder 88.15)
    - Southwest Myth Concordance - Original Myths, undated (Folders 89.1-89.3)
    - Southwest Myth Concordance - Preface, undated (Folder 89.4)
    - Southwest Myth Concordance, undated (Folders 89.5-89.9)
    - Southwest Myth Concordance, undated (Folders 90.1-90.14)
    - Southwest Notes, undated (Folders 91.1-91.19)
    - Indian Mythology, Ethics -- Notes, undated (Folder 91.20)
    - Concordance for Shoshone Folklore (?) -- Notes, undated (BOX 92)
    - Concordance for Shoshone Folklore -- Notes, undated (Folder 93.1)
    - Concordance for Shoshone Folklore, undated (Folders 93.2-93.11)
    - Concordance for Shoshone Folklore, undated (Folder 94.1)
    - Research on Indian Education -- Outline for Fieldwork, Guide for Volunteers, undated (Folder 94.2)
    - Purpose of the Research on Indian Education, undated (Folder 94.3)
    - U.S. Dept. of the Interior, Office of Indian Affairs -- Chicago Seminar, undated (Folder 94.4)
    - Research on the Development of Indian Personality -- Outline for Use in the Pilot Study, undated (Folder 94.5)
    - Research on the Development of Indian Personality - Analysis of the Authority System of Each Tribe, undated (Folder 94.6)
    - Research on the Development of Indian Personality -- Field Guide to the Study of the Development of Inter-Personal Relationships, undated (Folder 94.7)
    - American Indian Mythology Field Notes, undated (BOX 95)
    - Serrano Field Trip Notes, undated (BOX 96)
- SERIES XII. CULTURE AREA FILES
  - Culture Area Files - Africa, undated (Folder 97.1)
  - Culture Area Files - Austria, undated (Folders 97.2-97.5)
  - Culture Area Files - Belgium, undated (Folders 97.6-97.10)
  - Culture Area Files - Bulgaria, undated (Folder 97.11)
  - Culture Area Files - Burma, undated (Folder 97.12)
  - Background for a Basic Plan for Burma, undated (Folder 97.13)
  - Culture Area Files - China, undated (Folder 98.1)
  - Culture Area Files - China, undated (Folder 98.2)
  - Culture Area Files - Czechoslovakia, undated (Folders 98.3-98.6)
  - Culture Area Files - England, undated (Folder 98.7)
  - Culture Area Files - Finland, undated (Folder 98.8)
  - Culture Area Files - France, undated (Folders 98.9-98.12)
  - Culture Area Files - Greece, undated (Folder 98.13)
  - Culture Area Files - Germany, undated (Folders 99.1-99.9)
  - Culture Area Files - Holland, undated (Folders 100.1-100.11)
  - Culture Area Files - Holland, undated (Folders 101.1-101.11)
  - Culture Area Files - India, undated (Folder 102.1)
  - Culture Area Files - Indo-China, undated (Folder 102.2)
  - Culture Area Files - Ireland, undated (Folder 102.3)
  - Culture Area Files - Italy, undated (Folder 102.4-102.7)
  - Culture Area Files - Japan - Japanese Behavior Patterns, by Ruth Benedict, (TS) (Folder 102.8)
  - Culture Area Files - Japan - Japanese Behavior Patterns, by Ruth Benedict. Report to OWI. Mimeo, undated (Folder 102.9)
  - Culture Area Files - Japan - Japanese Origins, by Ruth Benedict, undated (Folder 102.10)
  - Culture Area Files - Japan - Social Structure Brochure, undated (Folder 102.11)
  - Culture Area Files - Japan - An Analysis of Japanese Ethics Textbooks and the Imperial Rescript on Education, by P. Ehret and E. Lockhard, (1945) (Folder 103.1)
  - Culture Area Files - Japan - Japanese Administration at the Local Level, by John Embree, (1944) (Folder 103.2)
  - Culture Area Files - Japan - Japanese Character Structure, by G. Gorer, (1942) (Folder 103.3)
  - Culture Area Files - Japan - Provisional Analytical Summary of Institute of Pacific Relations Conference on Japanese Character Structure, by M. Mead, (1944) (Folder 103.4)
  - Culture Area Files - Japan - Our Past in Modernizing Japan's Beliefs, by Dr. Henry Neumann, (1946) (Folder 103.5)
  - Culture Area Files - Japan - Muteki (Fog Horn), by Jiro Osaragi, (1934) (Folder 103.6)
  - Culture Area Files - Japanese OWI - Notes:, undated (Folder 103.7)
  - Japanese Suicide a Spiritual Act, Tokyo commentator says (OWI 31), undated (Folder 103.7)
  - Diary (typescript) of second lieutenant Hirano, a Platoon leader North of Templeton's Crossing, undated (Folder 103.7)
  - "The Japanese View of Life and Death", undated (Folder 103.7)
  - A Note on Japanese Suicide, undated (Folder 103.7)
  - Notes on Japanese Suicide, undated (Folder 103.7)
  - "What Shall be done about the Emperor", undated (Folder 103.7)
  - Problems in Japanese Morale Submitted for Study by Psychiatrists, undated (Folder 103.7)
  - Morale Handbook, undated (Folder 103.7)
  - Miscellaneous notes, undated (Folder 103.7)
  - Culture Area Files - Japan - OSS Tests, Pentagon, undated (Folder 103.8)
  - Culture Area Files - Japan - OWI Research Materials, undated (Folder 103.9)
  - Culture Area Files - Japan - Films, undated (Folder 103.10)
  - Culture Area Files - Japan - Psychiatry, undated (Folder 103.11)
  - Culture Area Files - Japan - Rorschach Tests, undated (Folder 103.12)
  - Culture Area Files - Japan - Women, undated (Folder 103.13)
  - Culture Area Files - Japan - Tokyo Mainichi Shimbun (Japanese Metropolitan Daily) - Translation (Report #22, 1945), undated (Folder 104.1)
  - Culture Area Files - Japan - OWI Daily Report - Foreign Radio Broadcasts (1945), undated (Folder 104.2)
  - Culture Area Files - Japan - Report of the U.S. Education Mission to Japan, (1946) (Folder 104.3)
  - Culture Area Files - Japan - Miscellaneous Notes, undated (Folders 104.4-104.6)
  - Culture Area Files - Japan - Research Notes, undated (Folders 104.7-104.9)
  - Culture Area Files - Japan - Bibliography, undated (Folders 105.1-105.3)
  - Culture Area Files - Japan - Quotes and Excerpts from Books on Japan, undated (Folders 105.4-105.6)
  - Culture Area Files - Japan - Interviews, undated (Folders 105.7-105.10)
  - Culture Area Files - Japan - Data Excerpts, undated (Folders 105.11-105.14)
  - Culture Area Files - Japan - Data Excerpts, undated (Folders 106.1-106.11)
  - Culture Area Files - Jews, undated (Folder 106.12)
  - Culture Area Files - Mexico, undated (Folder 106.13)
  - Culture Area Files - Norway, undated (Folder 106.14)
  - Culture Area Files - Portugal, undated (Folder 106.15)
  - Culture Area Files - Rumania, undated (Folders 107.1-107.9)
  - Culture Area Files - Rumania, undated (Folders 108.1-108.7)
  - Culture Area Files - Rumania, undated (Folders 109.1-109.7)
  - Culture Area Files - Russia, undated (Folders 110.1-110.4)
  - Culture Area Files - Spain, undated (Folder 110.5)
  - Culture Area Files - Thailand, undated (Folders 110.6-110.-10)
  - Culture Area Files - Turkey, undated (Folder 110.11)
  - Culture Area Files - Turkey, undated (Folder 110.12)
  - Culture Area Files - United States, undated (Folders 111.1-111.11)
  - Culture Area Files - Yugoslavia, undated (Folder 111.12)
- SERIES XIII. U. S. OFFICE OF WAR INFORMATION [OWI]
  - Applications of Anthropology to Social Problems, undated (Folder 112.1)
  - Notes on Captured Documents, undated (Folder 112.2)
  - Memo to Mr. Katz, undated (Folder 112.3)
  - Overseas Newsletter, undated (Folder 112.4)
  - Underground Activities, undated (Folder 112.5)
  - Planning for the Liberation of Europe, undated (Folder 112.6)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Folder 112.7)
  - Council for Democracy, undated (Folder 112.8)
  - Employment Data, undated (Folder 112.9)
  - OWI Consultants -- List; Correspondence with A - M (1943-1945), undated (Folder 112.10)
  - OWI Consultants -- Correspondence with P - W (1943-1945), undated (Folder 112.11)
  - Memo on Selection of Personnel in China, [1944], undated (Folder 112.12)
  - Educational Project for Strengthening the Cultural and Social Ties Between Allied and Neutral Nations, undated (Folder 112.13)
  - Unesco - 1947-1948, undated (Folder 112.14)
  - Unesco Seminar, 1948, undated (Folder 112.15)
- SERIES XIV. TESTS AND POLLS
  - Tests and Polls -- Details to be Observed, undated (Folder 113.1)
  - Tests and Polls -- Basic Table on Cultural Diversity, undated (Folder 113.2)
  - Tests and Polls -- Tests, undated (Folder 113.3)
  - Tests and Polls -- Replies of Experts to Questions on the Inheritance of Mental Traits, undated (Folder 113.4)
  - Tests and Polls -- The Gottschald Figures, undated (Folder 113.5)
  - Tests and Polls -- Bibliography for Research in Public Opinion Management, undated (Folder 113.6)
  - Tests and Polls -- Health Services and Medical Care for Children and Mothers, undated (Folder 113.7)
  - Tests and Polls -- Welfare Services for Children and Mothers, undated (Folder 113.8)
- SERIES XV. FRANZ BOAS, 1858-1947; Some of this material is available online at Alexander Street Press's Anthropology Commons.
  - Correspondence: Boas to Benedict, 1922-1930 (Folder 114.1)
  - Correspondence: Boas to Benedict, 1931-1932 (Folder 114.2)
  - Correspondence: Boas to Benedict, 1933-1938 (Folder 114.3)
  - Correspondence: Boas to Benedict, 1939-1940 (Folder 114.4)
  - Correspondence: Benedict to Boas, 1937-1939 (Folder 114.5)
  - Correspondence: Boas to Others, 1886, 1933-1942 (Folder 114.6)
  - Correspondence: Re: Boas, 1927-1934 (Folder 114.7)
  - Correspondence: Re: Boas, 1935-1936 (Folder 114.8)
  - Correspondence: Re: Boas, 1937-1947 (Folder 114.9)
  - Correspondence: Re: Boas, 1943-1946, 1958 (Folder 114.10)
  - Correspondence: Miscellaneous to Boas, 1925-1927, 1948 (Folder 114.11)
  - Boas -- Vita and Fragments, undated (Folder 115.1)
  - Boas -- Fragments, undated (Folder 115.2)
  - Boas -- Journal articles, undated (Folder 115.3)
  - Boas -- Laguna Tales, undated (Folder 115.4)
  - Boas and Edward M. David -- "Race: America's Social Barrier", undated (Folder 115.5)
  - Boas -- Lecture: "Race and Progress", undated (Folder 115.6)
  - Boas -- Lectures, undated (Folder 115.7)
  - Boas -- Obituaries, undated (Folder 116.1-116.4)
  - Boas Tribute by Benedict -- Draft, undated (Folder 116.5)
  - Boas Honorarium, undated (Folder 116.6)
  - Boas -- Printed Material, undated (Folder 116.7)
  - Boas -- Clippings and Tributes, undated (Folder 116.8)
- SERIES XVI. MARGARET MEAD (1901-1978)
  - Mead to Benedict: Research Notes and Memos, undated (Folder 117.1)
  - Correspondence: Condolence Notes, 1948 (Folder 117.2)
  - Correspondence: To Mead re: "A Lady of Culture", undated (Folder 117.3)
  - Correspondence: To Mead re: Benedict Obituary, 1948-1949 (Folder 117.4)
  - An Anthropologist at Work, (TS) (Folder 117.5-117.13)
  - An Anthropologist at Work -- First Working Draft, Vassar File, Parts 1-3, [mimeo] (BOX 118)
  - An Anthropologist at Work -- First Working Draft, Vassar File, Parts 4-6, [mimeo] (BOX 119)
  - Early poems and correspondence with Harriet Monroe, (mimeo) (Folder 120.1)
  - Letter to Bruce Bliven, (mimeo) (Folder 120.2)
  - Patterns of American Culture, (mimeo) (Folder 120.3)
  - The Study of Cultural Patterns in European Nations, (mimeo) (Folder 120.4)
  - Anthropology and Problems of Morale, (mimeo) (Folder 120.5)
  - A Reply to John Chamberlain, (mimeo) (Folder 120.6)
  - Remarks at Luncheon of Southern Conference, (mimeo) (Folder 120.7)
  - If I Were a Negro, (mimeo) (Folder 120.8)
  - The Bond of Fellowship, (mimeo) (Folder 120.9)
  - Sex Offenses: A Comparative View, (mimeo) (Folder 120.10)
  - A Delinquent Boy: Comments on a Life History, (mimeo) (Folder 120.11)
  - Malvina Hoffman, (mimeo) (Folder 120.12)
  - American Culture: A Comparative View, (mimeo) (Folder 120.13)
  - Franz Boas's Courage, (mimeo) (Folder 120.14)
  - Franz Boas Is Dead, (mimeo) (Folder 120.15)
  - Boas Says He'll Vote for FDR Because..., (mimeo) (Folder 120.16)
  - The Death of Freedom, (mimeo) (Folder 120.17)
  - Boas Challenges 'Biological Purge', (mimeo) (Folder 120.18)
  - Academic Freedom, (mimeo) (Folder 120.19)
  - Preserving Our Ideals, (mimeo) (Folder 120.20)
  - Why German-Americans Blame America, (mimeo) (Folder 120.21)
  - A Note from the American Ethnological Society, (mimeo) (folder 120.22)
  - Franz Boas, (mimeo) (Folder 120.23)
  - Prof. Franz Boas, President, American Association for the Advancement of Science, (mimeo) (Folder 120.24)
  - Review: Gregory Bateson: Naven, (mimeo) (Folder 120.25)
  - Review: Elsie Clews Parsons: Pueblo Indian Religion, (mimeo) (Folder 120.26)
  - Patterns of Culture, (mimeo) (Folder 120.27)
  - Teaching Notes on Field Methods, (mimeo) (Folder 120.28)
  - Review: Robinson Jeffers: Cawder [sic] and Other Poems, (mimeo) (Folder 120.29)
  - The Bo-Cu Plant [See unpublished ms. in 54.2], (mimeo) (Folder 120.30)
  - The Chance for Life, (mimeo) (Folder 120.31)
  - Journal: 1909, (mimeo) (Folder 120.32)
  - The Future of the Horse, (mimeo) (Folder 120.33)
  - Notes on Boas' "Methods" Lectures, (mimeo) (Folder 120.34)
  - North American Folklore, (mimeo) (Folder 120.35)
  - The Home of Evangeline, (mimeo) (Folder 120.36)
  - The Statue of Justice, (mimeo) (Folder 120.37)
  - The Passion of Giving, (mimeo) (Folder 120.38)
  - The Sewing Society, (mimeo) (Folder 120.39)
- SERIES XVII. EDWARD SAPIR (1884-1939)
  - Sapir Obituary, undated (Folder 121.1)
  - Sapir Biographical Sketch, undated (Folder 121.2)
  - Sapir -- Poetry Manuscripts, undated (Folders 121.3-121.7)
  - Sapir -- Original Poetry Typescripts, undated (Folder 121.8)
  - Sapir -- Published Poetry, undated (Folders 121.9-121.12)
- SERIES XVIII. PHOTOGRAPHS
  - RUTH FULTON BENEDICT and FAMILY
    - Ruth Fulton Benedict as a child, young woman, undated (Folder 122.1)
    - Ruth Benedict, European trip, 1909-1910 (Folder 122.2)
    - Ruth Benedict, circa 1924 (Folder 122.3)
    - Ruth Benedict (by Marie Eichelberger), circa 1930 (Folder 122.4)
    - Ruth Benedict during early years of marriage, undated (Folder 122.5)
    - Ruth Benedict with Blackfoot (?) Indians, undated (Folder 122.6)
    - Ruth Benedict as a mature woman, undated (Folder 122.7)
    - Portrait of RFB by Bachrach, circa 1937 (Folder 40.4 (Oversize))
    - Sketch of Ruth Benedict: "Prefiguring Death," by Erik Erikson, undated (Folder 122.8)
    - Ruth and Margery Fulton as children, undated (Folder 122.9)
    - Ruth Benedict with Margery Fulton Freeman's grandchildren, undated (Folder 122.10)
    - Ruth Benedict with Margery Fulton Freeman's children, circa 1916 (Folder 122.11)
    - Margery Fulton Freeman, undated (Folder 123.1)
    - Bertrice Shattuck Fulton, undated (Folder 123.2)
    - Photocopies of photographs in VC Class box, VC 1885 (Bertrice Shattuck Fulton's class), undated (Folder 123.3)
    - Dr. Frederick S. Fulton, 1857-1889 (Benedict's father), undated (Folder 123.4)
    - El Greco -- Fra Felix Mortensis Palaviciano, undated (Folder 123.5)
    - Myra Shattuck (Auntie My), undated (Folder 123.6)
    - Shattuck Family, undated (Folder 123.7)
    - Ruth, Stanley Benedict, Bertrice Shattuck Fulton, undated (Folder 123.8)
    - Stanley Benedict, undated (Folder 123.9)
    - Shattuck Farm, undated (Folder 123.10)
    - Summer home at Lake Winnipesaukee, New Hampshire, undated (Folder 123.11)
    - Homes at Bedford Hills and Douglas Manor, New York, undated (Folder 123.12)
  - COLLEAGUES
    - Margaret Mead, undated (Folder 123.13)
    - Franz Boas, undated (Folder 123.14)
    - Edward Sapir, undated (Folder 123.15)
  - SOUTHWEST
    - Mescalero trip [?], undated (Folder 123.16)
    - Indians of the Southwest, undated (Folder 123.17)
  - MISCELLANEOUS
    - Miscellaneous Photographs, undated (Folder 123.18)
    - Lantern slides [used by RFB for teaching?], undated (Box 124)
- SERIES XIX. MAPS
  - Maps, undated (Box 125)
- SERIES XX. Realia
  - Benedict's portable typewriter, undated (Range 47)